A husband. A wife. A millionaire. A proposal.
Indecent Proposal is a romance, drama film directed by Adrian Lyne.
John Gage offers a down-on-his-luck yuppie husband $1 million for the
opportunity to spend the night with the man's wife.
John Gage, played by Robert Redford.
Diana Murphy, played by Demi Moore.
David Murphy, played by Woody Harrelson.
Mr. Shackleford, played by Seymour Cassel.
Jeremy, played by Oliver Platt.
Day Tripper, played by Billy Bob Thornton.
Indecent Proposal is a 1993 American erotic drama film directed
by Adrian Lyne and written by Amy Holden Jones.
It is based on the 1988 novel by Jack Engelhard, in which a couple's marriage is disrupted by a
stranger's offer of a million dollars for the wife to spend the night with him.
It stars Robert Redford, Demi Moore, and Woody Harrelson.
The film received a mostly negative response from critics for the
contrivances and implausibilities of its story.
It also sparked controversy, with feminists arguing the film's premise
promotes prostitution and the treatment of women as property.
Despite this, the film was a box office success and grossed nearly $267 million worldwide
on a $38 million budget, becoming the sixth highest-grossing film of 1993.
The film explores themes of adultery, love of one's
life, gambling, roulette, las vegas.
The tone is emotional.